100. Raflesia, the corpse flower. Repulsive, foul, stinking. Would you guess that all
these adjectives apply to a flower? Raflesia is the type of flower to which all
those words apply. It grows in Southeast Asia. It's very rare, and it is more commonly
called the corpse flower. It got this nickname because of its horrible smell. People say
Raflesia flowers smell like rotting flesh. Raflesias are unusual for a lot of reasons,
not only for their smell. First of all, they are parasites. They grow on a particular kind
of rainforest vine. Sadly, as the rainforests disappear, Raflesia is also disappearing. The
only parts of Raflesia plants that can be seen are their flowers, which are huge. The biggest,
Raflesia arnoldii can be one meter across and weigh 11 kilograms. It's the heaviest single
flower on Earth. Even the smallest blossoms are quite large, at 12 centimeters across.
Raflesia flowers are usually reddish brown with a white pattern that can look like warts. They
smell so terrible in order to attract flies, not bees, which pollinate them. Flies land on the
flowers, looking for meat, and take pollen with them when they fly away. This helps Raflesia
reproduce. Currently, Raflesia needs some help. For all its great size, it is a delicate genus.
The flowers live only a few days. They usually grow in untouched locations, and many of them
are difficult to keep alive outside of their natural habitat. Right now, the number of
Raflesia flowers in the world is decreasing. So the more reproducing it does, the better.
If we want wild, stinky, unusual Raflesias to stay alive on the Earth, we must work to protect them
and study them, even if we have to hold our noses while we do so.